<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on bortox.it :tada: on bortox.it - Andrea Bortolotti</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on bortox.it :tada: on bortox.it - Andrea Bortolotti</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Content license: [ :link: CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 16:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bortox.it/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix fastboot error boot partition is smaller than boot image when installing DivestOS on Fairphone</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/fix-fastboot-error-divestos-fairphone-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/fix-fastboot-error-divestos-fairphone-3/</guid><description>Following the instructions on the DivestOS official website, after rebooting to the unlocked bootloader one should do:
If fastboot.zip available: $ fastboot update divested-version-date-dos-device-fastboot.zip If recovery.img available: $ fastboot flash recovery divested-version-date-dos-device-recovery.img
I downloaded both files to install DivestOS the fastboot way, but with my Fairphone 3 it didn&amp;rsquo;t work
When trying to do fastboot update divested-19.1-20220808-dos-FP3-fastboot.zip
-------------------------------------------- Bootloader Version...: Baseband Version.....: Serial Number........: A123BCEF4567 -------------------------------------------- extracting android-info.txt (0 MB) to RAM.</description></item><item><title>Convert jekyll blog images to avif and webp with jekyll picture tag</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/jekyll-blog-webp-avif-images/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/jekyll-blog-webp-avif-images/</guid><description>I have a blog with over 100 articles, mainly Compiti Scolastici (:it: School assignments), where I also convert images to the recent .avif and .webp formats.
Why convert images to modern formats? # Why did I do it? Mainly for three reasons:
The score of some pages with many images on PageSpeed was sometimes less than 90/100 and it mildly infuriated me, because the website average is 98/99 out of 100.</description></item><item><title>Optimize png images with pngquant</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</guid><description>Surfing on F-droid - an open-source app store - I discovered the Atomize app. This app aims to reduce the size of an image in png format, often by up to 70%.
In my case, using a few screenshots or manga scans, the reduction often reaches 50% with negligible (unnoticeable) losses in image quality.
I was amazed, so I opened the About app screen where I discovered that the app is simply a front-end of the open-source binary pngquant.</description></item><item><title>About bortox.it :tada:</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/about-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/about-website/</guid><description>Website map # The site (the lair of the Borto) is divided into two sections:
Person :neutral_face: School :school_satchel: :neutral_face: Person # Photo :camera: # The personal section contains a collection of :camera: photos taken by me. Photography has always interested me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had several compact cameras since primary schools.
Blog 💻 # The computer blog (:it:,:uk:) instead contains guides and notes to improve the experience of using various Linux 💻 and Android 📱 distros.</description></item><item><title>404 :confused:</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/404/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/404/</guid><description>It seems that the page just requested does not exist.
Go to :house: menu Go to the collection of photos 📷 Go to the tech blog (:it:,:uk:) Go to Compiti e appunti scolastici (🇮🇹) Go to 🔍 Trovaparadigmi GUI (🇮🇹)</description></item><item><title>You are offline. Check your internet connection.</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/offline/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/offline/</guid><description>:mobile_phone_off: You are offline. Check the connection.
bortox.it works also offline.
How does bortox.it work offline? # Since bortox.it is a PWA (Progressive Web App) it can be partly browsed even offline! Every page you visit online is stored for one hour in the browser&amp;rsquo;s cache.
Every time you visit a webpage on bortox.it, a service worker copies temporarily on the device:
the page you are visiting the pages linked in the page you are visiting Available offline pages: # These pages are available for one hour on your device.</description></item><item><title>Show page visitor count on Hugo static site with Congo theme and Goatcounter analytics</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/add-page-views-hugo-goatcounter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/add-page-views-hugo-goatcounter/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ll use the Goatcounter json api to get the current page views for each article in my hugo static site, and show views in the article meta, in this case next to the reading time, or just below, as you can see. It&amp;rsquo;s like those old sites with a visit counter on the bottom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy of bortox.it</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/privacy/</guid><description>bortox.it protects the privacy of its users.
bortox.it is not doing any profiling
If you think that the way we process your personal data with bortox.it is infringing the law, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.
Server Location: USA (Fastly hosting with Github Pages)
Third party services used on-site # Cookie: The website does not store cookies on visitors&amp;rsquo;devices.
The website uses Goatcounter to get stats about the most visited pages, GDPR-compliant services which anonymize every single visit and do not store personal information.</description></item><item><title>Brief summary of Shakespeare's Macbeth</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/macbeth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 10:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/macbeth/</guid><description>Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s main source for the tragedy Macbeth was Raphael Holinshed&amp;rsquo;s Chronicles of England, Scotland and Ireland.
According to some critics the tragedy may have been commissioned by the monarch James II, the successor of Elizabeth the I. He was Scottish, he liked magics and he was intrested in everything connected with magicians and witchcraft, on which he also wrote a book. Macbeth is a tragedy and this tragedy is set in Scotland.</description></item><item><title>Yunohost setup SSH key access only for user account</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</guid><description>&lt;p>After installing YunoHost on my VPS on a few days, I checked &lt;em>fail2ban&lt;/em> logs. Fail2ban is a Python service to ban IPs that try to access your server by reading the access logs, as SSH log, Nginx log by using regular expressions to catch malicious IPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long story short, there were about ~800 failed SSH login attempts, and the rising number annoyed me, so I decided to allow only SSH access with asymmetric key pairs and disallow authentication with passwords to be a bit safer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anglo-Saxon period, Gregory I, Alfred the Great and the Normans</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-anglo-saxon-history/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 17:41:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-anglo-saxon-history/</guid><description>The Anglo-Saxon period seems like a long and boring era, but it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely, luckily!
Counting epic poems such as Beowulf and elegies as Deor&amp;rsquo;s Lament, this is the incipit of English Literature, where it all starts.
After romanised Celts were left alone by the Roman withdrawal, several Germanic tribes invaded Britain.
Jutes, Angles and Saxons A.K.A. Anglo-saxons invaded Britain and settled southern of Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s wall.
We&amp;rsquo;re not going to talk about the early stages of the Anglo-saxon society much, since we&amp;rsquo;ll spend more time on the Beowulf poem and the Norman invasions.</description></item><item><title>The Norman Invasion, from William I to Henry II</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-norman-invasion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 14:17:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-norman-invasion/</guid><description>William, duke of Normady, after winning against Anglo-Saxons gained the &amp;ldquo;Conqueror&amp;rdquo; alias and made drastic changes to the society. He changed the justice system, introducing sheriffs and the feudal system, he also introduced Norman Rule and wrecked the Anglo-Saxon ruling class.
The Norman Rule # The Norman Rule deprived Anglo-Saxons of their properties and land and replaced Anglo-Saxon aristocrats with Norman aristocrats, so now the ruling class spoke French.
Birth of Middle English # If you were there, after William&amp;rsquo;s conquest, you&amp;rsquo;d hear three different languages in Britain:</description></item><item><title>Create a Discord Webhook and send messages with Python</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/discord-webhook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/discord-webhook/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article I will expose the fastest method to create a Discord webhook, that is a link that can be used with Python to send messages in specific channels of a server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anglo Saxon Society, the King and the Scop.</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-anglo-saxon-society/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-anglo-saxon-society/</guid><description>The Anglo Saxon society had a hierarchical structure.
Since Anglo Saxons were Germans, the Germanic values were held in great consideration:
loyalty physical courage (to fight) personal freedom bravery The King # The king, at the top of the society, had its own group of warriors, the thanes, bound by loyalty to him - the most important value. King and thanes togheter form the comitatus.
Usually the king also created a mid-hall, like the one we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in Beowulf, which is a large room in the castle, where people joined to celebrate victory and to drink.</description></item><item><title>The Roman Conquest of Britain</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-roman-conquest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-roman-conquest/</guid><description>Julius Caesar was the first Roman emperor to conquer Britain, although only nominally in 55 B.C..
The main reasons were two:
Britain had a good soil to farm. Celts were helping Gauls, and they had to be taught a lesson He didn&amp;rsquo;t tryhard and did this just to scare the Celts from helping Gauls, so he failed and lost.
Emperor Claudius, about ~90 years later, in 43 A.D., took control of central and south eastern Britain.</description></item><item><title>The Celtic Society</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-celtic-society/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/compiti/english-literature/old-english/the-celtic-society/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the origins of English culture and literature in this page, right from the beginning.
The first inhabitants of British Isles vere the Iberians, many centuries B.C.
We say "B.C." (Before Christ) or "B.C.E" for events happened before the year 0, and instead "A.D." (Anno Domini) or "C.E." (Common Era) for events happened after the year 0. After the Iberians (our book - LitHub - doesn&amp;rsquo;t even talk about them!</description></item><item><title>Install Ruby and Jekyll on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenSuse is a distro that I can recommend. Fast and stable, European and also easy to customize thanks to YAST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first days of use, however, I encountered a problem: &lt;strong>I could not install Jekyll, the program written in Ruby&lt;/strong> that I use to compile most of my static sites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change DNS on Android 9+ and block ads</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/come-bloccare-le-pubblicita-su-android-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/come-bloccare-le-pubblicita-su-android-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, we will explain a simple and safe strategy to be able to block most advertisements in apps and when surfing the Internet with an Android 9 or higher device via private DNS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>