<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on BBlog on bortox.it 🦅 the cuckoo's nest</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on BBlog on bortox.it 🦅 the cuckoo's nest</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Content license: [ :link: CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 16:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bortox.it/en/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix fastboot error boot partition is smaller than boot image when installing DivestOS on Fairphone</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/fix-fastboot-error-divestos-fairphone-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/fix-fastboot-error-divestos-fairphone-3/</guid><description>Following the instructions on the DivestOS official website, after rebooting to the unlocked bootloader one should do:
If fastboot.zip available: $ fastboot update divested-version-date-dos-device-fastboot.zip If recovery.img available: $ fastboot flash recovery divested-version-date-dos-device-recovery.img
I downloaded both files to install DivestOS the fastboot way, but with my Fairphone 3 it didn&amp;rsquo;t work
When trying to do fastboot update divested-19.1-20220808-dos-FP3-fastboot.zip
-------------------------------------------- Bootloader Version...: Baseband Version.....: Serial Number........: A123BCEF4567 -------------------------------------------- extracting android-info.txt (0 MB) to RAM.</description></item><item><title>Convert jekyll blog images to avif and webp with jekyll picture tag</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/jekyll-blog-webp-avif-images/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/jekyll-blog-webp-avif-images/</guid><description>I have a blog with over 100 articles, mainly Compiti Scolastici (:it: School assignments), where I also convert images to the recent .avif and .webp formats.
Why convert images to modern formats? # Why did I do it? Mainly for three reasons:
The score of some pages with many images on PageSpeed was sometimes less than 90/100 and it mildly infuriated me, because the website average is 98/99 out of 100.</description></item><item><title>Optimize png images with pngquant</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</guid><description>Surfing on F-droid - an open-source app store - I discovered the Atomize app. This app aims to reduce the size of an image in png format, often by up to 70%.
In my case, using a few screenshots or manga scans, the reduction often reaches 50% with negligible (unnoticeable) losses in image quality.
I was amazed, so I opened the About app screen where I discovered that the app is simply a front-end of the open-source binary pngquant.</description></item><item><title>Show page visitor count on Hugo static site with Congo theme and Goatcounter analytics</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/add-page-views-hugo-goatcounter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/add-page-views-hugo-goatcounter/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ll use the Goatcounter json api to get the current page views for each article in my hugo static site, and show views in the article meta, in this case next to the reading time, or just below, as you can see. It&amp;rsquo;s like those old sites with a visit counter on the bottom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yunohost setup SSH key access only for user account</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</guid><description>&lt;p>After installing YunoHost on my VPS on a few days, I checked &lt;em>fail2ban&lt;/em> logs. Fail2ban is a Python service to ban IPs that try to access your server by reading the access logs, as SSH log, Nginx log by using regular expressions to catch malicious IPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long story short, there were about ~800 failed SSH login attempts, and the rising number annoyed me, so I decided to allow only SSH access with asymmetric key pairs and disallow authentication with passwords to be a bit safer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create a Discord Webhook and send messages with Python</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/discord-webhook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/discord-webhook/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article I will expose the fastest method to create a Discord webhook, that is a link that can be used with Python to send messages in specific channels of a server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install Ruby and Jekyll on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenSuse is a distro that I can recommend. Fast and stable, European and also easy to customize thanks to YAST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first days of use, however, I encountered a problem: &lt;strong>I could not install Jekyll, the program written in Ruby&lt;/strong> that I use to compile most of my static sites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change DNS on Android 9+ and block ads</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/come-bloccare-le-pubblicita-su-android-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/come-bloccare-le-pubblicita-su-android-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, we will explain a simple and safe strategy to be able to block most advertisements in apps and when surfing the Internet with an Android 9 or higher device via private DNS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>