<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on bortox.it 🦅 the cuckoo's nest</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on bortox.it 🦅 the cuckoo's nest</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Content license: [ :link: CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bortox.it/en/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimize png images with pngquant</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/optimize-png-pngquant/</guid><description>Surfing on F-droid - an open-source app store - I discovered the Atomize app. This app aims to reduce the size of an image in png format, often by up to 70%.
In my case, using a few screenshots or manga scans, the reduction often reaches 50% with negligible (unnoticeable) losses in image quality.
I was amazed, so I opened the About app screen where I discovered that the app is simply a front-end of the open-source binary pngquant.</description></item><item><title>Yunohost setup SSH key access only for user account</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/yunohost-ssh-allow-user-only/</guid><description>&lt;p>After installing YunoHost on my VPS on a few days, I checked &lt;em>fail2ban&lt;/em> logs. Fail2ban is a Python service to ban IPs that try to access your server by reading the access logs, as SSH log, Nginx log by using regular expressions to catch malicious IPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long story short, there were about ~800 failed SSH login attempts, and the rising number annoyed me, so I decided to allow only SSH access with asymmetric key pairs and disallow authentication with passwords to be a bit safer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install Ruby and Jekyll on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed</title><link>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bortox.it/en/article/ruby-open-suse/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenSuse is a distro that I can recommend. Fast and stable, European and also easy to customize thanks to YAST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first days of use, however, I encountered a problem: &lt;strong>I could not install Jekyll, the program written in Ruby&lt;/strong> that I use to compile most of my static sites.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>